<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-3072" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Bollo's Cafe &amp; Bakery</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">Bollo's is a cozy cafe and bakery located on Draper Road, right down the street from Squires Student Center. Bollo's is known for their baked goods, which are made from scratch daily. They also provide a warm, small-town atmosphere within their cafe. </shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Bollo's Cafe (Exterior)</title><image href="bollos-exterior.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of the outside of Bollo's Cafe and Bakey. </alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Accessibility and Location: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">Located just right across the street from Coffeeholics, Bollo's has the same very convenient location for VT students. It can be tricky for two coffee shops to be in the same spot in town, but I think Bollo's age and charm helps it appeal to Blacksburg locals in addition to college students. Coffeeholics is a bit more trendy and can get loud in the large space, Bollo's smaller size and homey atmosphere make it a calmer place to get work done or catch up with a friend. However, the same location challenges that Coffeeholics faces apply to Bollo's too, like the lack of available parking. Unlike Coffeeholics, Bollo's does not have an order-ahead option, which may make it seem less convenient, but I think they do that to preserve the small town vibe and quiet nature of the cafe. I'm giving it a 4 for accessibility and location because although there is not convenient parking, its location is still nearby for students and Blacksburg locals. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Aesthetic and Vibe: 5</title><p class="- topic/p ">To be fair, aesthetic and vibe can be very subjective. Some people love a loud, bustling coffee shop where the barista is yelling out coffee orders. When I'm in a rush, I too can appreciate this atmosphere and dedication to speed. However, if I'm going out of my way to sit down in a coffee shop and do work or meet up with a friend, I want the environment to be as peaceful and cozy as possible. For me, Bollo's captures that aesthetic perfectly. Bollo's provides an escape from all the hustle and bustle of a college campus with its dim lighting, quiet music, homemade pastries, and baristas that are never in a rush. It may not have nice couches or super comfy chairs, but the layout reminds me of any hometown locally owned coffee shop, and to me that is worth more. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Quality of Coffee and Food: 4.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">Compared to Halwa and Coffeeholics, Bollo's beats them out by a landslide. There's nothing quiet like a baked good made from scratch, and Bollo's provides these daily. Their coffee is also genuinely very good. They also provide a wide selection of coffee and teas, meeting any customer's needs. </p></section><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Muffin and Latte</title><image href="bollos-muffin.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of a blueberry muffin and latte from Bollo's. </alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Overall Experience: 5</title><p class="- topic/p ">In case my thoughts on Bollo's weren't already clear, let me reiterate that I think Bollo's captures the essence of what a coffee shop is supposed to be. In a world of unfriendly, fast-paced Starbucks', Bollo's reminds us of the community and quality a cafe should provide. If you are ever in Blacksburg, this is the one cafe I would recommend visiting before you leave. I recommend any of their muffins and their chai latte. You won't be disappointed. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Total Score: 18.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">With all scores added up, Bollo's receives a 18.5 out of 20. </p></section><p class="- topic/p ">All Bollo's images sourced from Yelp.</p></body></topic>