<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-1998" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Halwa</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">Halwa is a Lebanese bakery and cafe located on North Main Street. It has many tables, couches, and chairs, often serving as a site for bible studies, studying students, and friends catching up. There is a very large menu, it perhaps is even a little overwhelming, but Halwa knows how to cover all of its bases, offering almost every type of tea and latte. It also has an extensive bakery display, producing Lebanese-inspired pastries like baklava and other classic cafe items like cookies and muffins. </shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Halwa Bakery &amp; Cafe</title><image href="halwa-bakery.jpeg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of Halwa's sign outside the cafe. There is also string lights and outdoor seating. </alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Accessibility and Location: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">Halwa is located on North Main Street and is a relatively quick walk from campus. For students who live off campus near Progress Street, it is also a convenient location. There is a parking lot but in the middle of a school day it may be hard to snag a spot. There is no drive-thru or order ahead option available but drinks are made within a few minutes. I give it a 4 out of 5 for accessibility and location because it is close to campus and there is usually parking available.</p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Aesthetic and Vibe: 5</title><p class="- topic/p ">Halwa's aesthetic and vibe is top tier. It is always well-decorated, offering a warm and inviting environment to all of its visitors. String lights, decorative pillows, and seasonal decorations create the perfect atmosphere for doing homework or catching up with friends. I give Halwa a 5 out of 5 for its aesthetic and vibe because it is always clean, well-decorated, and cozy. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Quality of Coffee and Food: 3.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">Halwa is clearly making an effort with their menu. They offer a wide variety of drinks and food, attempting to appeal to a broad audience. However, I have rarely had a good drink here. Their lattes are always off, whether the espresso is sour or there's too much milk or syrup, it never wows me. Unfortunately the same goes for their food. They offer an abundance of pastries and I have tried a few of them. Most of the time I find them too bready, not sweet enough, or lacking flavor. Pastries are left in the display case for a while, which may contribute to their lack of quality. Despite this, I do appreciate Halwa's effort with their food and drinks. Even when I don't love my latte, I always love the atmosphere and environment Halwa provides. </p><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title "> Lebanese Latte</title><image href="halwa-latte.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of a latte from Halwa. </alt></image></fig><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title "> Baklava Pastry</title><image href="halwa-food.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of a baklava pastry from Halwa. </alt></image></fig></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Overall Experience: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">I am giving Halwa a 4 for overall experience because although the coffee isn't always stellar, the vibe inside the cafe is. I also appreciate its very convenient location and that there's usually parking available. I have made a lot of great memories in  Halwa with my friends and I am thankful for that.  </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Total Score: 16.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">With all scores combined, Halwa receives a 16.5 out of 20 points.</p></section><p class="- topic/p ">All Halwa images sourced from Yelp.</p></body></topic>