<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-8052" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Best of Blacksburg: Coffee Shops</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">Hello, and welcome to my guide on the best coffee shops in Blacksburg! As a senior at Virginia Tech, I have frequented many Blacksburg cafes over the years and I have identified what exactly makes a good cafe and what makes a bad one. Everyone needs a good place to get a cup of coffee, whether you’re a student studying for finals, an alumnus visiting, or if you just want some hot cocoa to walk around town with,  you need a coffee shop you can rely on. I will consider the relevant cafes in the area and rate them according to criteria including accessibility and location, aesthetic and vibe, quality of coffee and food, and overall experience. A detailed description of each category of criteria can be found below.  </shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Coffee Mug</title><image href="coffee-background.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of a coffee cup and a spoon full of coffee beans.</alt></image></fig><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Rating Criteria:</b> Each category of criteria will be rated 1 through 5, 1 being the lowest score and 5 being the highest. With all the scores added up, each cafe will receive a rating out of 20.</p><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Accessibility and Location (1-5 rating) </b></p><ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li ">Does it have a drive-thru?</li><li class="- topic/li ">Is there parking available?</li><li class="- topic/li ">Can you order ahead?</li><li class="- topic/li ">How close is it to campus?</li></ul><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Aesthetic and Vibe (1-5 rating)</b></p><ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li ">Is there seating inside?</li><li class="- topic/li ">Is it relatively quiet for doing homework or studying?</li><li class="- topic/li ">Is the interior clean and well-decorated?</li><li class="- topic/li ">Is the exterior clean and well-kept?</li><li class="- topic/li ">Does the coffee shop’s vibe work well for hanging out with friends or doing homework?</li></ul><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Quality of Coffee and Food (1-5 rating)</b></p><ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li ">Is the coffee actually good?</li><li class="- topic/li ">Does the menu provide a wide variety of drinks (i.e. espresso drinks, coffee, tea, matcha, chai, hot chocolate)? </li><li class="- topic/li ">Does the menu provide food options?</li><li class="- topic/li ">Is the food high quality?</li></ul><p class="- topic/p "><b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Overall Experience (1-5 rating) </b></p><p class="- topic/p ">In my professional opinion, an ideal coffee shop provides a two-fold experience to meet the needs of a variety of customers.</p><ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li ">It can be a convenient grab-and-go experience. This is for busy individuals who are in need of an espresso drink immediately and don’t have time to wait in a long line. The cafe ideally operates to make coffees quickly and efficiently to help their customers get out the door. </li><li class="- topic/li ">It can also be a comfy, stay-a-while cafe. This is for the students who are looking for a place to get a coffee, sit down, and study for a couple hours. Or perhaps for individuals who want to catch up with their friends over a cup of coffee in a warm atmosphere. </li></ol><p class="- topic/p ">If a coffee shop can meet both of these needs, it is creating the best overall experience for its customers. </p></body></topic>