<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-9740" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Starbucks</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">I would be remiss if I neglected to review the coffee shop behemoth that Starbucks is. Conveniently, there are three Starbucks locations in the Blacksburg area, but I will be reviewing the one closest to campus - the Virginia Tech North End Center location. This Starbucks is on campus and just a quick walk from Turner dining hall. Many students turn to Starbucks because of its consistency and reliability. </shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Starbucks: Virginia Tech North End Center</title><image href="starbucks-outside.png" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of someone holding up an iced Starbucks drink outside the store.</alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Accessibility and Location: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">This Starbucks is located at the Virginia Tech North End Center on Turner Street Northwest. It is just a quick walk away from the academic side of campus near Turner and McBryde. This makes it a very convenient location for students and visitors who are walking through campus. As far as parking goes, there is a few street parking spots as well as the North End Garage. While it's on  a different side of campus than Bollo's and Coffeholics, it is still convenient during the week for many individuals. Perhaps one of Starbucks' best features is its order ahead option. This is helpful for any customer on the go.  </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Aesthetic and Vibe: 3.5 </title><p class="- topic/p ">The thing about Starbucks is that the vibe is always going to be the same, regardless of which Starbucks you go to. The interior decor rarely varies between stores. It is not necessarily a bad aesthetic, there are always lots of seating options and warm, seasonal decor. It does however, lack originality and creativity. I'm giving it a 3.5 because Starbucks' interior does offer a reliable spot for students to do homework or grab a coffee. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Quality of Coffee and Food: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">There tends to be some public debate over whether Starbucks' coffee and food is good or bad. Some say the espresso tastes terrible and the food is average, while others go through the drive-thru religiously every day. I think regardless of all this public discussion, Starbucks does remain consistent in their quality of food and drink. If I order a latte two days in a row, I can guarantee that they will taste the same. If I were to go to a coffee shop like Dunkin, that would not be true. Starbucks has strict recipes that all baristas have to follow when making the drinks, which produces a very consistent experience across all Starbucks. To me, Starbucks food should only be ordered when necessary. The breakfast sandwiches are okay but not great and even their baked goods like the pumpkin loaf and banana bread are just alright. If you're in need of a quick breakfast or sweet treat, Starbucks food can get the job done but may leave you feeling a little disappointed. </p></section><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Bakery Display Case</title><image href="starbucks-inside.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of Starbucks' display case with bakery items. </alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Overall Experience: 3.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">For me, the overall experience at Starbucks is mostly favorable. I always get my drink quickly, I can order-ahead if I want to, and the ambiance is good enough inside that I could do some homework there if I needed to. While it may not be the best option for coffee shops, it's definitely not the worst, and you at least always know what to expect. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Total Score: 15</title><p class="- topic/p ">With all scores added up, Starbucks receives a 15 out of 20 points.</p></section><p class="- topic/p ">Images sourced from VT Starbucks' Instagram and Yelp.</p></body></topic>