<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-2946" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Coffeeholics</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">Coffeeholics is a spacious cafe located on Draper Road, just down the street from Squires Student Center. It offers a wide variety of drinks and pastries. Coffeeholics provides ample space and seating both outside and inside. Its convenient location appeals particularly to students, as it is right next to campus. </shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Coffeeholics Cafe</title><image href="coffeeholics-sign.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of Coffeeholics' exterior sign and logo, with the words "Espress Yourself!"</alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Accessibility and Location: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">If you are a Virginia Tech student and living on campus, Coffeeholics' location is hard to beat. It is just a few feet away from the Squires Student Center and several student dorms including CID. However, for anyone who does not regularly come to campus or live in the area, the location becomes much more difficult to get to. The only parking nearby is metered street parking or the Squires parking lot, which is reserved for faculty and staff members Monday-Friday. Nevertheless, Coffeeholics is the quintessential coffee spot for many students because of its location. They also have an order-ahead option as well as delivery through Doordash. This is helpful for busy students and individuals who need their coffee on the go. I rate it a 4 because although parking is tricky, it is still accessible and convenient for many people. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Aesthetic and Vibe: 4.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">Coffeeholics provides ample space and seating for its customers. The cafe has an open layout and lots of natural light floods through the front windows. It is always clean and well-decorated with lots of art on the walls and seasonal decorations. My one note for their interior design would be that their chairs are pretty uncomfortable, which makes me not want to hang out and study there for too long. Also, some of their art and decorations could be considered tacky and cringe-worthy. But hey, some would say cheesy motivational quotes  are what make a cafe. </p></section><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Interior</title><image href="coffeeholics-interior.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of the inside of Coffeeholics cafe. There are numerous tables and students studying at them.</alt></image></fig><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Tacky Wall Art</title><image href="cringy-sign.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of a tacky art sign in Coffeeholics. It says, "Caffeine in one hand, confidence in the other". </alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Quality of Coffee and Food: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">Coffeeholics offers a wide range of drinks, including everything from cold brew to lattes to matcha to smoothies. Over the past few years they have also expanded the food they offer. They now have a full display case of muffins, bagels, cupcakes, and more.  When I first started going to Coffeeholics during my freshman year at Tech, the quality of their drinks was not good. I would order an iced matcha and it would be served to me lukewarm and loaded down with syrup. I had the same experience with their lattes. However, I recently returned for an iced latte and I was pleasantly surprised. While it wasn't the best latte I've ever had, it was definitely improved from what I remember and I'm happy to say I would gladly go back. While their food also isn't phenomenal, I can say the same - the quality has definitely improved. If I wanted a truly good breakfast or an exceptionally good coffee, I wouldn't go to Coffeeholics. However, for an afternoon pick-me-up or a quick catch up with friends, I know I could rely on this cafe.</p></section><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Bakery Case</title><image href="muffin-case.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of Coffeeholics' case of pastries with muffins and bagels. </alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Overall Experience: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">Overall, Coffeeholics is a very solid cafe option. It offers decent coffee and food options and there is always seating available. Perfect for catching up with friends, studying for an exam, or just grabbing a latte, Coffeeholics has got you covered. I took one point off for the lack of  available parking, which could prevent many people from making the trek.</p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Total Score: 16.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">With all scores added up, I give Coffeeholics a 16.5 out of 20.</p></section><p class="- topic/p ">All Coffeeholics images sourced from Yelp.</p></body></topic>