<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-4571" xml:lang="en-us" class="- topic/topic "><title class="- topic/title ">Our Daily Bread</title><shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">Our Daily Bread is located about a mile away from campus on South Main Street. They offer breakfast, lunch, and dinner. It is a very popular destination for brunch on the weekends. They also have specialty bakery items. Although it is not  just a cafe, Our Daily Bread is a very popular coffee and breakfast spot. </shortdesc><body class="- topic/body "><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Our Daily Bread</title><image href="ourdailybread-exterior.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of the outside of Our Daily Bread.</alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Accessibility and Location: 4.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">Our Daily Bread is not within walking distance of campus but there is plenty of parking available. Although it may be less convenient for students, the cafe being off campus helps create a peaceful atmosphere inside. Our Daily Bread also offers an order ahead option. </p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Aesthetic and Vibe: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">Our Daily Bread has a homey, southern comfort feel about it. Some may find the decor outdated, but I think it is classic and sweet. While Our Daily Bread may not be an ideal spot for studying because it operates more like a restaurant, it is a great place for grabbing coffee or breakfast with a friend. Although sometimes it can be very crowded, making it too loud and less enjoyable.</p></section><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Inside of Our Daily Bread</title><image href="ourdailybread-inside.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of the inside of Our Daily Bread. Lots of people sitting down. </alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Quality of Coffee and Food: 4.5</title><p class="- topic/p ">Because Our Daily Bread functions like a restaurant, it is clear they put more effort into their food. I have really enjoyed everything I've eaten here, particularly their breakfast. They also specialize in bakery items, and their display case is always full of cookies, cakes, and decadent pastries. </p></section><fig class="- topic/fig "><title class="- topic/title ">Our Daily Bread Bakery Case</title><image href="ourdailybread-bakerycase.jpg" class="- topic/image "><alt class="- topic/alt ">Picture of Our Daily Bread's bakery display case, revealing lots of cookies and pastries. </alt></image></fig><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Overall Experience: 4</title><p class="- topic/p ">Overall, Our Daily Bread creates a very warm and enjoyable experience for every customer. Although sometimes it gets very busy and hectic inside, it is usually a great spot for breakfast or coffee. I wouldn't recommend it for students who need a place to study, but it definitely can provide a great study break escape.</p></section><section class="- topic/section "><title class="- topic/title ">Total Score: 17</title><p class="- topic/p ">With all scores combined, Our Daily Bread receives 17 out of 20 points. </p></section><p class="- topic/p ">All Our Daily Bread images sourced from Yelp. </p></body></topic>